<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Excel RSS Feed</title>
    <link>https://YourWebsiteOrPlaceholder.com</link>
    <description>Feed generated from Excel approvals</description>
<item>
    <title>Moore Czech Republic Expands Operations – Acquires PP Business Services and AK AUDIT
</title>
    <category>Test</category>
    <description>Moore Czech Republic, a consulting, auditing, and technology group, has acquired PP Business Services and AK AUDIT, strengthening its Moore Accounting CZ and Moore Audit CZ divisions.  This acquisition significantly expands the group's offerings in accounting outsourcing, payroll processing, financial services, tax advisory, and statutory audits.  PP Business Services, combining legal expertise with accounting and financial management, aligns perfectly with Moore's growth strategy.  AK AUDIT, established in 1997, brings a strong team and extensive experience in audit and tax services, including full representation before authorities.  The combined expertise of these acquisitions adds approximately 25 employees and over 22 million CZK in annual revenue to Moore Czech Republic, bolstering its existing team of 70 audit professionals and over 110 employees in outsourcing, accounting, and tax consulting.  The merger also positions Moore Czech Republic for growth in ESG and sustainability audits.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech Republic s.r.o.</link>
    <pubDate>
Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech Republic s.r.o.</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>Changes to Fixed-Term and Part-Time Contracts May Negatively Impact Employment Flexibility in the Czech Republic
</title>
    <category>Test</category>
    <description>New Czech regulations regarding employment contracts (DPP and DPČ) mandate monthly reporting of all DPPs to the Czech Social Security Administration (ČSSZ), regardless of income.  This includes even those earning under 10,000 Kč, previously exempt from social security contributions.  While the 10,000 Kč limit remains, the added administrative burden significantly impacts businesses, increasing costs and workload for personnel departments.

Experts predict this will reduce the flexibility of the Czech labor market, potentially discouraging the use of DPP contracts for short-term tasks.  Companies might shift towards full-time employment or external collaborations with self-employed individuals (OSVČ) to mitigate administrative complexities.  While the government aims to increase transparency and improve employee conditions, concerns remain regarding reduced flexibility, especially given demographic trends and technological advancements.

The Czech Republic, while relatively flexible compared to other EU nations, lags behind in areas like part-time employment (6% vs. EU average of 13.7%).  Further hindering flexibility are low rates of remote work and limited support for lifelong learning, especially for older workers.  Increased investment in flexible work arrangements, remote work infrastructure, and continuous professional development are suggested to improve the Czech labor market's dynamism and competitiveness.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech Republic s.r.o.</link>
    <pubDate>
Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech Republic s.r.o.</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>Despite staff shortages, Czechs over 55 believe finding work is a problem due to age
</title>
    <category>Test</category>
    <description>A survey by MOORE Czech Republic reveals that 85.2% of Czech respondents over 55 believe age is the primary barrier to finding new employment.  This perception is consistent across the 55-59 and 60-65 age groups.  Despite a tight labor market, companies struggle to engage this experienced workforce, often possessing multilingual skills and extensive experience gained since the early 1990s.  These individuals represent a valuable pool of talent with at least 5-10 years of potential career remaining.

The study highlights employers' concerns about older workers' ability to adapt to technological advancements and a perceived preference for younger employees.  Prejudices regarding productivity and motivation also affect hiring practices.  To overcome this, companies need a "mental transformation" in their HR strategies, understanding the needs of older workers and tailoring recruitment methods accordingly.  Flexibility in working arrangements is crucial, with many older workers lacking this option.  Benefits such as cultural events and further education are valued more highly than family-oriented or sports-focused benefits commonly offered.

Respondents suggested flexible hours, technology training, and health support programs as beneficial.  Increased awareness of the contributions of older workers and more information on suitable job opportunities were also highlighted as important.  While many feel their skills are utilized, a significant portion believe they could offer more to their employers.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech Republic s.r.o.</link>
    <pubDate>
Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech Republic s.r.o.</guid>
</item>  </channel>
</rss>
