<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Excel RSS Feed</title>
    <link>https://YourWebsiteOrPlaceholder.com</link>
    <description>Feed generated from Excel approvals</description>
<item>
    <title>Moore Advisory CZ: State Could Save Up to CZK 337 Million Annually by Adjusting Payments for Social Care Stays
</title>
    <description>A Czech Ministry of Labour and Social Affairs analysis by Moore Advisory CZ suggests that adjusting payment terms for social care facilities could save the state budget up to 337 million crowns annually.  The study explored the possibility of increased client and family contributions for care in senior homes and facilities for people with disabilities.  While 52% of clients have someone who could contribute, current contribution rates are only 27%.

The analysis involved a survey of 1,000 clients and considered the financial capacity of both clients and their relatives to cover costs.  Proposed changes, similar to alimony laws, would require contributions from relatives, capped at 20% of their disposable income after living expenses.  The analysis includes safeguards for clients and relatives.

Currently, public funds cover the shortfall when client incomes are insufficient.  The proposed changes could significantly reduce this burden; however, increased administrative costs must be factored in.  Germany and Austria were used as models for incorporating private resources to fund social care.  The average monthly cost for basic care in October 2022 was nearly 14,500 crowns per client.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech s.r.o</link>
    <pubDate>
  Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT
</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech s.r.o</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>Moore Czech Republic Expands Consulting Services to Slovakia
</title>
    <description>Moore Czech Republic, in collaboration with Moore Slovakia, is expanding its operations in Slovakia.  Through their joint venture, Moore Consulting SK, they have acquired Radvise Group, a consulting firm serving both public and private sector clients.  This acquisition is a strategic move to better serve existing clients operating in both Czech and Slovak Republics and to capitalize on the Slovakian market's potential for ICT and management consulting.

Radvise Group, led by Ivan Lužica, who now heads Moore Consulting SK, brings extensive experience in process optimization, cost reduction, and performance enhancement.  The firm also specializes in EU-funded project management and large investment project assistance.  With Radvise Group's €2 million+ revenue and ten additional management consulting experts, Moore Czech Republic significantly strengthens its service offerings and aims to become a top 10 consulting firm in Slovakia.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech s.r.o</link>
    <pubDate>
  Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT
</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech s.r.o</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>Staying Effective and Not Going Crazy: Moore Czech Republic Joins Global Workplace Stress Reduction Initiative
</title>
    <description>Moore Czech Republic, part of Moore Global, joined the Mindful Business Charter to prioritize employee well-being and reduce workplace stress.  High stress significantly impacts physical and mental health, relationships, and often leads to absenteeism.  A recent Ipsos study revealed that 60% of Czechs experienced significantly life-impacting stress last year, with over 25% taking days off due to stress;  39% of Gen Z individuals missed work due to this.

The Charter promotes initiatives such as improved meeting management, reduced emails, and respecting employees' downtime.  Moore Czech Republic already integrates these practices, further demonstrating their commitment.  The company offers workshops like "How to Stay Effective and Not Go Crazy," providing practical stress management and work-life balance tips.  They also encourage physical activity through initiatives such as the "Moore to the Moon" challenge and a local "WALKING CHALLENGE 10K," promoting employee health while supporting charitable causes.  These efforts underscore Moore's dedication to a healthier and more supportive work environment.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech s.r.o</link>
    <pubDate>
  Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT
</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech s.r.o</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>Taxing non-financial benefits will put pressure on wage growth. It will also make recruitment more difficult for companies.
</title>
    <description>The Czech government's proposed restriction on tax benefits for non-monetary employee perks will negatively impact the Czech labor market and economy, warn experts from Moore Czech Republic.  Employees view these benefits as part of their compensation, and their removal will likely increase pressure for higher salaries.  This will make it harder for companies to attract skilled workers, especially in a tight labor market with record-low unemployment.

The experts argue the measure is ill-conceived, as the potential revenue increase for the state budget is questionable and far outweighed by the negative consequences.  The loss of benefits, often valued in thousands of crowns monthly, will create significant inflationary pressure. Businesses rely on these perks to attract and retain talent, impacting their competitiveness and potentially leading to a loss of skilled employees in whom they’ve invested.

Furthermore, the elimination of these benefits will severely harm third parties, such as sports facilities and cultural event organizers, who depend on this revenue stream. For some, this could prove financially devastating.  The overall impact could significantly destabilize the already fragile Czech economy.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech Republic</link>
    <pubDate>
  Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT
</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech Republic</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>Moore Czech Republic Expands Consulting Services to Slovakia
</title>
    <description>Moore Czech Republic, in collaboration with Moore Slovakia, is expanding its operations in Slovakia.  Through their joint venture, Moore Consulting SK, they have acquired Radvise Group, a consulting firm serving both private and public sector clients. This acquisition is a strategic move, enabling Moore to better serve its existing clients operating in both Czech Republic and Slovakia, while also capitalizing on the Slovakian market's potential for ICT and management consulting.  Radvise Group, led by Ivan Lužica, who becomes the managing partner of Moore Consulting SK, brings extensive experience in process optimization, cost reduction, and performance enhancement.  Their expertise also includes EU-funded project management and large-scale investment project assistance.  This acquisition adds approximately €2 million in revenue and 10 management consulting experts to Moore Czech Republic.  The combined entity aims to become a top 10 consulting firm in Slovakia.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech Republic</link>
    <pubDate>
  Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT
</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech Republic</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>Reskilling as an Elevator to Higher Professional and Salary Levels: Interest is Growing, Support is Not
</title>
    <description>The Czech Republic underutilizes retraining courses, despite their crucial role in adapting to a rapidly changing job market and the demands of digital technologies. While interest is growing, only 8.3% of Czechs aged 25-74 participated in a retraining course in the four months prior to a 2023 prosperity index survey, significantly lower than the EU average of 12.7%.  Increased employer support, particularly for specific age groups, could improve participation.

In the first half of 2023, 20,118 people enrolled in retraining, a 39% increase year-on-year, with nearly half participating in digitally focused programs funded by the National Recovery Plan.  This reflects declining employer demand for low-skilled workers, with those seeking upskilling often possessing basic, vocational, or secondary education.  Retraining offers opportunities for career advancement, regardless of age or current profession, as exemplified by individuals ranging from cleaning staff pursuing further education to professional athletes obtaining coaching licenses.  Online learning increasingly incorporates AI training, highlighting the vital role of retraining in digital transformation.

Over half of retraining participants are aged 35-55, but older individuals (55+) represent a skilled workforce with valuable experience and a willingness to learn. Employers should not overlook this group and should offer supportive conditions, including flexible work hours and training opportunities.  Success in retraining requires personal motivation, overcoming potential barriers like lack of employer support, financial constraints, time limitations, and fear of new technologies.  However, evidence shows that it's never too late to learn and adapt.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech Republic</link>
    <pubDate>
  Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT
</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech Republic</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>ESG Reporting Subject to New Rules: The CSRD Directive Will Shape Its Form from the New Year
</title>
    <description>The EU's Corporate Sustainability Reporting Directive (CSRD) mandates stricter non-financial reporting, significantly altering how companies showcase their sustainability efforts.  It enforces standardized ESG (Environmental, Social, Governance) data reporting, demanding transparent and reliable information on environmental, social, and governance impacts. This aims to create consistent, comparable reports for investors and stakeholders to better assess companies' sustainability.  Successful ESG reporting requires early preparation, as the directive necessitates a thorough "double materiality" analysis – considering both a company's impact on its environment and the environment's impact on the company – and mandatory audits.  Inaccurate or incomplete data can lead to reputational and legal issues.

Effective implementation involves integrating ESG into the core business strategy, making it a crucial part of decision-making rather than a side initiative.  This requires cross-departmental collaboration, ensuring ESG is not solely managed by specialists but becomes a company-wide commitment.  The CSRD aims to prevent "greenwashing" by demanding data-backed reports, showcasing both successes and challenges.  Companies should also perform a gap analysis to identify areas needing improvement and strive to exceed minimum legal requirements, becoming sustainability leaders rather than merely complying with regulations.  Successful ESG implementation under CSRD enhances a company's growth and long-term competitiveness.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech Republic</link>
    <pubDate>
  Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT
</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech Republic</guid>
</item><item>
    <title>Three out of four employees want a four-day work week. Interest is higher than two years ago.
</title>
    <description>A recent survey by Moore Czech Republic reveals that nearly half of Czech employees would support a four-day work week, with an additional 28% expressing some level of agreement.  This positive sentiment has grown since a similar 2021 survey, showing an increase from 61% to 67% in favor.  Interestingly, 65% of respondents in both surveys indicated they would dedicate more time to work if the week were shortened.

Around 30% believe a four-day week is feasible without increased productivity, while nearly 22% think it would work with enhanced employee performance.  Younger employees (18-26) showed the strongest support (83%), while enthusiasm declined with age, although even the 54-65 age group showed 77% support. Men expressed more skepticism than women.  Currently, the Czech Republic is not planning a nationwide four-day work week, but the trend aligns with similar experiments in other European countries, notably Britain, which has reported increased productivity and reduced employee turnover.  Czech companies are increasingly exploring flexible work arrangements, and a four-day week is seen as a potential tool to attract talent in the current labor shortage.
</description>
    <link>Moore Czech Republic</link>
    <pubDate>
  Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT
</pubDate>
    <guid>Moore Czech Republic</guid>
</item>  </channel>
</rss>
